

# LUCAS LOIS

TECHNICAL LEADER 

◆ CAPITAL FEDERAL, ARGENTINA 

+54 9 1157035553

## • DETAILS •

Capital Federal Argentina +54 9 1157035553 lucaslois95@gmail.com

LINKS

**Website** 

° SKILLS °

PHP

Laravel

Javascrypt & Typescript

NodeJS

React

Arquitectura de Software

POO

AWS

Git

Linux

SQL

HTML, CSS & Bootstrap

LANGUAGES

Español

English

## PROFILE

Hi there! I. I'm an Argentinian software developer with over 6 years of experience, passionate about programming and computer science in general.

Currently, I work as a Technical Leader primarily using Laravel, PHP, NodeJS, Typescript, React, and Redux, in addition to supporting the rest of the team in Architecture and project estimations.

In parallel, I participate in the hiring process for new developers by conducting technical interviews.

I enjoy constantly researching new technologies and methodologies to improve the quality of my work and my professional profile. I have solid knowledge in algorithmics, object-oriented programming, REST API development, and architecture. Among my skills, I highlight my communication abilities, intellectual curiosity, fast learning capacity, and passion for solving problems with software.

## EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

# Technical Leader at Braintly, CABA

December 2019 — Present

- As Tech Lead, I continue to perform my duties as a developer on various projects, utilizing the latest technologies.
- I participate in the hiring process by conducting technical interviews for the recruitment of new developers.
- Definition of methodologies and architectures for new projects.

#### Ssr. Software Developer at Braintly

October 2018 — December 2019

- Complete backend development (REST API) for projects of more than 5 clients using: PHP, Laravel, NodeJS, Typescript, React, Redux, and SQL.
- Use of SCRUM methodology with Jira.
- Infra and DevOps tasks configuring pipelines in Github Actions, AWS, and Digital Ocean.
- Support in development estimation.
- Documentation of APIs using Swagger.

### Desarrollador PHP at Deux IT, CABA

January 2017 — October 2018

- Design, development, and maintenance of the corporate website using: HTML, CSS, JS, and PHP.
- Installation, configuration, and maintenance of various ARIS 9.8 and ARIS 10 production environments.
- Full and customized development of management systems for multiple clients of the company using: PHP, Laravel 5.6, MySQL, Bootstrap, JS, CSS, and HTML.
- Maintenance, bug fixing, and development of new enhancements in existing systems for clients of the company (PHP/MySQL).

## Soporte IT at Beecker Consulting, Mexico City

May 2014 — December 2016

- Design, development, and maintenance of a multilingual corporate website
- Development of internal web systems for Recruitment of new personnel and Mentoring
- Installation, configuration, and maintenance of various web systems (Moodle, Wordpress, etc.)
- Providing technical support to company collaborators
- Providing training on ARIS 7.2
- Assisting in the installation of an ERP System

# Technologies used:

- HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, PHP, MySQL
- Moodle, Wordpress
- Frameworks/Libraries: jQuery, Bootstrap

# **EDUCATION**

Licenciatura en Análisis de Sistemas, Universidad de Buenos Aires

January 2014 — January 2019

(Incompleta)

Analista de Sistemas, Instituto ORT, CABA

August 2022 — Present